AKSHAY SHELAR.

 $+91-8275605151 \diamond Pune, India$

Email \diamond LinkedIn \diamond GitHub \diamond Portfolio

PROFILE

With 3 years of professional experience, I have actively contributed to the full lifecycle of Web application development. I am proficient in modern web technologies including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and frameworks/libraries such as Angular, TypeScript, NodeJS, Bootstrap, NestJS, ReactJS, and TypeORM.

SKILLS

Technical Skills Angular, Node Js, HTML5, CSS, Java-Script, Bootstrap, React Js, TypeORM

Secondary Skills REST APIs, Docker, Git, Elastic Search, Unit Testing

Soft Skills Communication Skills, Problem-Solving Abilities, Teamwork and Collaboration

Language English, Hindi, Marathi

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer
Intellitek.AI(SmarTek21)

June 2024 - Present
Pune, India

Project: Dubai National Insurance(DNI) (Feb 2024 - Present)

• Led the maintenance of **product services**, ensuring timely delivery of urgent updates and resolving **security vulnerabilities** to maintain code integrity.

Software Engineer - Trainee

April 2022 - May 2024

Pune, India

2016

SmarTek21

Project: Document Smart Search (Dec 2023 - Feb 2024)

Diploma in Mechanical, MIT College of Engineering, Pune

• Leveraged **Angular** to design and implement **dynamic**, **user-friendly interfaces** with a focus on UI/UX best practices. Utilized **Node.js** for backend development, ensuring **efficient API calls** and seamless integration between frontend and backend systems.

Project: User Management (Aug 2023 - Present)

- Utilized **Node.js** with **TypeORM** for efficient database interactions and Angular for intuitive user interfaces. Implemented features such as user **Authentication**, **Authorization**, and **profile management**, ensuring a seamless and secure user experience.
- Created comprehensive unit tests using frameworks like Jasmine and Karma for Angular, and Mocha and Chai for Node.js. Achieved 80% code coverage, ensuring high test coverage and early bug detection, contributing to a more stable and reliable application.

Project: Smart Bot Platform and Bot Builder (April 2022 - Aug 2023)

• Adhered to **standard coding practices** and guidelines to produce clean, maintainable, and scalable code. Conducted regular code reviews and refactoring to **enhance performance** and **reliability**.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer, Digikull Internship	2022
Bachelor of Engineering, Pune University Mechanical - First Class with Distinction	2019

Mechanical - First Class